<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bond on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/bond/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bond on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/bond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Casino Royale (2006) - 144 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/casino_royale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/casino_royale/</guid>
      <description>Released at a time when the franchise had been overtaken in spectacle by Bourne and Mission: Impossible, Martin Campbell’s second slightly-harder Bond reboot wisely eschews a central action sequence in favour of an intimate and wonderfully tense extended poker game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Is Not Enough (1999) - 128 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_world_is_not_enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_world_is_not_enough/</guid>
      <description>A Bond film infused with the spirit of New Labour from the opening action scene focused on the triumphalist national symbolism of the Millennium Dome and the economic regeneration of the Isle of Dogs to the scenes where MI6 sets up temporary headquarters in Scotland acting as an allegory for devolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomorrow Never Dies (1997) - 119 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tomorrow_never_dies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tomorrow_never_dies/</guid>
      <description>There’s something interesting about these Bond films from the End of History. Wai Lin (Michelle Yeoh) refers to Bond as a “decadent agent of a corrupt Western power” and it’s a joke but a joke that the film feels no need to seriously repudiate or counter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoldenEye (1995) - 130 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/goldeneye/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/goldeneye/</guid>
      <description>The old is dying and the new cannot be born. Behind the onanistically triumphalist surface symbolism of this first post-Cold War Bond film with its literal graveyards of Soviet symbols and its rampages through freshly-capitalist Russia and communist Cuba, there is a hint of rot at the heart of both Bond and by extension England.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
