<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bond on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/bond/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bond on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/bond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No Time to Die (2021) - 163 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/no_time_to_die/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/no_time_to_die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It may be strange to say at the end of &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/bond/&#34;&gt;a series reviewing late-Bond through a political lens&lt;/a&gt; but NO TIME TO DIE works by focusing on the personal. Instead of the thin political themes of &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/quantum_of_solace/&#34;&gt;QUANTUM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/spectre/&#34;&gt;SPECTRE&lt;/a&gt;, we get a back-to-basics terrorist supervillain with an evil lair and zero motivation for his genocidal ambitions but also an actual narrative arc for James Bond and a script that gives Daniel Craig something to work with: the early scenes of Bond too broken by trauma to trust anyone are some of his best work in the role. There’s a smidge too many lines of dialogue that overexplain things to the audience but this is the first Bond script since &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/casino_royale/&#34;&gt;CASINO ROYALE&lt;/a&gt; that does more than shuttle us from set piece to set piece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectre (2015) - 148 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/spectre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/spectre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been here before,” starts Sam Smith’s theme for SPECTRE. And we have. SPECTRE recycles so many elements from previous Bonds in a rearrangement that is less than the sum of its parts: a seven-letter title and insight into Bond’s past like SKYFALL; a shadowy criminal organisation like QUANTUM; Bond and his love interest getting to know each other on a train like CASINO ROYALE; a high-speed boat chase down the Thames starting from the MI6 Building like WORLD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skyfall (2012) - 143 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/skyfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/skyfall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It would be hyperbole to blame SKYFALL for the ills of the United Kingdom after the 2015 general election. And yet…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum of Solace (2008) - 106 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/quantum_of_solace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/quantum_of_solace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A victim of sloppy pre-production and the AMPTP’s failure to negotiate, QUANTUM OF SOLACE was clearly not ready to be made. Quite apart from the undercooked script, Eon Productions should have waited to settle with Kevin McClory’s estate so their shadowy criminal organisation could have been Spectre instead of the damp squib that is Quantum (though interesting in retrospect to use ‘Q’ as a symbol for their globalist conspiratorial organisation). The too-many action sequences are directed without a sense of spatial cohesion and the attempted themes around climate change, green(e)washing, and Western imperialist involvement in South American coups are too blunt to be incisive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Casino Royale (2006) - 144 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/casino_royale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/casino_royale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Released at a time when the franchise had been overtaken in spectacle by Bourne and Mission: Impossible, Martin Campbell’s second slightly-harder Bond reboot wisely eschews a central action sequence in favour of an intimate and wonderfully tense extended poker game. It’s a brilliant sequence, all the more so for never wasting time spelling out the rules of Texas hold ‘em for the audience and trusting that, even if they don’t know a flush from a straight, the acting and direction will communicate the tension. The action sequences are good (especially free-running in Madagascar) but that central section makes the film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World Is Not Enough (1999) - 128 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_world_is_not_enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_world_is_not_enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Bond film infused with the spirit of New Labour from the opening action scene focused on the triumphalist national symbolism of the Millennium Dome and the economic regeneration of the Isle of Dogs to the scenes where MI6 sets up temporary headquarters in Scotland acting as an allegory for devolution. Compare and contrast this film’s depiction of power moving from London to Scotland to the country’s appearance in 2012’s SKYFALL where it’s positioned as a dead and decaying ancestral home, an denuded place where no-one would ever look for Bond and M. Unfortunately, like New Labour, the film ultimately gets tied up in incoherent political and corporate plans involving oil and Russian oligarchs before getting bogged down by confused speeches and corny one-liners that simply aren’t meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tomorrow Never Dies (1997) - 119 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tomorrow_never_dies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tomorrow_never_dies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s something interesting about these Bond films from the End of History. Wai Lin (Michelle Yeoh) refers to Bond as a “decadent agent of a corrupt Western power” and it’s a joke but a joke that the film feels no need to seriously repudiate or counter. There’s no later scene where Wai Lin is shown the importance of the West or capitalist democracy: there’s just an ironic acceptance that this is how China perceives the UK. It expresses a sense of confidence and security in capitalist liberal democracy that simply doesn’t exist anymore. Similarly, it’s interesting that the villain is a recognisable capitalist entity—Rupert Murdoch’s press—rather than a vaguely ideologically-motivated terrorist or a disgruntled agent of a ‘rogue state’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GoldenEye (1995) - 130 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/goldeneye/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/goldeneye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The old is dying and the new cannot be born. Behind the onanistically triumphalist surface symbolism of this first post-Cold War Bond film with its literal graveyards of Soviet symbols and its rampages through freshly-capitalist Russia and communist Cuba, there is a hint of rot at the heart of both Bond and by extension England. Quite apart from the villain being a British double agent, Bond’s final act of killing for himself and not “for England” expresses the libertarian individualism that would eventually metastasize into Brexit. You get the sense from Martin Campbell’s first soft reboot of Bond that his direction was striving for more than could be allowed by the script’s caricatures—all the women and Bond himself come across as uncannily inhuman—and the ADRed quips clearly added in post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
