<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christmas on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/christmas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christmas on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/christmas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deck the Halls (2006) - 93 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/deck_the_halls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/deck_the_halls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to avoid reading this film through a class lens whereby Matthew Broderick’s character, Dr. Steve Finch, is positioned as the reasonable one in the central conflict entirely through his middle-class status rather than through any reasonable actions. His opulent suburban home and his status in a professional job establish him as the middle-class norm which is intruded upon by Buddy Hall (Danny DeVito), a debt-ridden working-class interloper whose Christmas decorations are offensive not because they disturb Steve per se but simply because they’re gauche compared to the Finch’s WASPy ‘traditional’ Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lot No. 249 (2023) - 30 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lot_249/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lot_249/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A forgettable adaptation. Mark Gatiss’ new episodes consistently fail to capture the eerie atmosphere of the ‘70s &lt;em&gt;A Ghost Story for Christmas&lt;/em&gt; shorts and they end up feeling awfully flat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Green Knight (2021) - 130 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_green_knight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_green_knight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What stands out in David Lowery’s telling of &lt;em&gt;Sir Gawain and the Green Knight&lt;/em&gt; is the film’s poetic depiction of a land perched between paganism and Christianity, in that boundary space between competing ways of life: a solstice of cultures, a time—like Christmas—when the barriers between worlds are made thin. The pagan forces of nature and the kingdoms of Christendom are at war throughout the film, fighting over a land that is already saturated with the red bloodshed of centuries. And what’s it all for? In the end, even as he dreams of running from his own mortality, Gawain (Dev Patel) discovers that he’s already rotting from the inside out. The green that The Lady (Alicia Vikander) tells us will take everything already took him and his kingdom long ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Muppet Christmas Carol (1992) - 89 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_muppet_christmas_carol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_muppet_christmas_carol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every frame of this film is burned into my brain after watching it once every two years or so since I was old enough but it remains delightful every time, joyous every time, and I well up every time during the scene of the Christmas yet-to-come where Tiny Tim (Jerry Nelson) has died. It’s wild that this iteration of Kermit (Steve Whitmire), one not performed by Jim Henson, might be the most frequently-seen Kermit. Disney is leaving money on the table by not doing other literary adaptations with Muppets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo Godfathers (東京ゴッドファーザーズ) (2003) - 93 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tokyo_godfathers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tokyo_godfathers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A thoroughly charming found-family Christmas anime which mines comedy from some very tragic scenes and finds a delightful balance between those tragicomic elements. The film excels at weaving a twisting narrative but never feeling tangled. Some aspects of the portrayal of queerness through the character of Hana (Umegaki Yoshiaki) feel regressive in 2023 and through my particular cultural lens as a white Anglo critic but on the whole it feels like Kon Satoshi had his heart in the right place with it particularly as the characters deepen and reveal themselves throughout the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Merry Scottish Christmas (2023) - 84 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_merry_scottish_christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_merry_scottish_christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An American family discovers their ancestral Scottish titles and, to the delight of locals who love licking the boot of the British Empire, must decide whether to take on the vast tracts of land that their ancestors stole in the Clearances despite knowing nothing about the ecological responsibilities of Highland land ownership. The strangest element is the intense and flirtatious relationship between the brother and sister who continually talk about how “close” they used to be and have more chemistry than any other couple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Christmas Break (2023) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_christmas_break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_christmas_break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple who communicate almost exclusively in bombshell decisions go away to Éire for Christmas and make decisions at each other. This bad Christmas movie gets points for actually being filmed in the Republic rather than a soundstage in Canada and for Justin Long who brings a measure of charm to a character who would be quite irritating on paper. I also enjoyed the young lad who gets self-help-pilled towards the end. Unfortunately one subplot hinges on a Christmas Eve Gaelic football match which goes on for like five to ten minutes onscreen and is very tedious to watch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B&amp;B Merry (2022) - 85 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bb_merry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bb_merry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The older women in this would have better chemistry as a lesbian couple than as sisters. I presumed the script had made them sisters so as not to alienate the conservative audience for this specific subgenre of bad Christmas romcoms. But then I thought, is that really the audience for these films? Has it not totally shifted to extremely online, irony-poisoned Letterboxd users like me who treat the whole month of December as a long MST3K episode? Are there still people watching this subgenre sincerely?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Cupcakes (2018) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/christmas_cupcakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/christmas_cupcakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;X xxxxxxxxxxx xxxxxxx &amp;lsquo;xxxxx xxxxxxxx xx xxxxxxx&amp;rsquo; Xxxxxxxxx xxxx xxxx xxxxxxx xxxxxxxxxxxx xxx x xxxxxx lack of background music in scenes where you’d expect it. But then! The second half injects genuine energy through Kristian Bruun’s (queer-coded?) villainous artisan baker and, most significantly, through Greg Lawson channelling Ricardo Montalbán at his most scenery-chewing in his role as Chef Paolo Joeljinjo, an enigmatic but strangely compelling judge of a local TV baking competition show. Lawson’s performance alone saves the film and honestly made me glad we didn’t turn the film off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Psycho (2000) - 102 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/american_psycho/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/american_psycho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one scene, Patrick Bateman (Christian Bale) and his yuppie colleagues briefly list all the progressive social issues that they’re aware of as ostensible members of society but clearly care about less than haircuts and business cards. It’s short but so incisively effective as a satire of capital’s liberalwashing tendencies that it’s a perfect synecdoche for the strength of Mary Harron and Guinevere Turner’s script: a script that is broad enough to be laugh out loud funny in its heightened ridiculousness yet precise enough to so devastatingly satirise a particular breed of Reaganite monster which has only grown in cultural prominence since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Very English Christmas (Christmas in the Cotswolds) (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_very_english_christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_very_english_christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xxxxx&amp;rsquo;x x xxxxxxxxxx xxxx xx xx made that A VERY ENGLISH CHRISTMAS is a psychological reflection of the main character’s narcissism in how it moves hollow characters around on the chessboard of the narrative with no regard for their feelings or interiority. Kate’s (Kimberley Nixon) American mother is brought over to England from California at one day’s notice for the wedding of her ex-husband’s daughter and the mother is blankly accepting of this: she doesn’t even get a scene with her ex-husband to say ‘hello’ let alone acknowledge complex feelings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Christmas Exchange (2020) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_christmas_exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_christmas_exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xxxx xxx xxxxx Xxxxxxxx xxxxxxx xx xxxx xxxx, xxxx xxx xxxxxxxxxxxxx xxxxxx xx Xxxxxx. Xxxxxxxxxxxx xxxxxxx xxx xxx xxxxxxxxxxxx xxxxx of ‘London’ use stock footage of Glasgow streets and Glasgow buildings specifically around George Square and Merchant City. This is the kind of detail that might be lost on anyone but an amateur film critic like me who has lived in both London and Glasgow and is why you should commission me for your publication. The film itself is bland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes Wide Shut (1999) - 159 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eyes_wide_shut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eyes_wide_shut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bill Harford (Tom Cruise) is a conflicted Wife Guy, frustrated by his realisation of his wife as a sexual being and simultaneously unable / unwilling to consummate his abstract sexual desire with any of the women (or men) who throw themselves at him as he descends into Dantean circles of dream. His libidinal fantasies—a beautiful and eager sex worker; a nymphet child—become completely unmoored from actual sexual desire at the dream’s deepest level with an orgy of anonymous vanilla sex free from blemishes, sweat, or any of the gritty humanness that actually makes sex exciting. His inability to consummate with anyone but his wife turns this into a nightmare as his mask literally falls away and the crowd threaten to strip him bare. Tom Cruise’s subsequent career has been a long affirmation of Kubrick’s casting as he has lost himself in dreams—cinema, endless blockbusters, a cult—while still retaining the tortured sense of inadequacy behind his eyes that we see here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Hearts (1973) - 35 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lost_hearts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lost_hearts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not my favourite of Lawrence Gordon Clark’s Ghost Stories for Christmas, LOST HEARTS is altogether too literal. Adaptations of James work best when the haunting is diffuse, unknowable, and tied to the ghost of England.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
