<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GFT on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GFT on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Saltburn (2023) - 131 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saltburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saltburn/</guid>
      <description>Emerald Fennell follows up her debut with another black comedy dealing with a vector of privilege: this time, the British class system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Lives (2023) - 106 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/past_lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/past_lives/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been to that carousel in Brooklyn: walked around the riverfront and had my photo taken in front of the Manhattan backdrop by the person I love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jurassic Park (1993) - 127 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/jurassic_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/jurassic_park/</guid>
      <description>A film with incredible depth of detail. On the big screen for the 30th anniversary, I caught so many small background details in almost every frame that catch the eye but aren’t visually overwhelming and make the world feel lived in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uptight (1968) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/uptight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/uptight/</guid>
      <description>In the depth of his drunken despair, Tank (Julian Mayfield) stands in front of a carnival mirror and gives a funhouse description of the Black revolution to some credulous rich white people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afire (Roter Himmel) (2023) - 103 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/afire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/afire/</guid>
      <description>Continuing a series of films about deeply frustrating German men. Leon (Thomas Schubert) is always watching people from a distance and talking to them through windows accentuating the gulf he perceives between himself and other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oppenheimer (2023) - 181 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/oppenheimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/oppenheimer/</guid>
      <description>If it’s possible for one scene to radically elevate an entire movie, it’s the scene where Oppenheimer (Cillian Murphy) gives his victory speech and the sound drops away apart from a solitary scream and the quiet aftermath of nuclear devastation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbie (2023) - 114 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/barbie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/barbie/</guid>
      <description>How does an intelligent, socially conscious woman approach writing a Barbie movie in the year 2023? Greta Gerwig approaches it in a way not unlike Charlie Kaufman adapting Susan Orlean’s The Orchid Thief: by deconstructing what it means to write a Barbie movie in our current sociopolitical moment and acknowledging the multivalent, complicated, and contradictory nature of Barbie’s image throughout the 20th Century and into the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asteroid City (2023) - 105 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</guid>
      <description>ASTEROID CITY serves as something of an artistic statement for this period of Wes Anderson’s filmmaking, overtly discussing existential themes around meaning and, in particular, finding meaning through art that emphasise Anderson’s complicating of modernism and postmodernism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rushmore (1998) - 93 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</guid>
      <description>Quite apart from the blossoming of his distinctive aesthetic (developed in collaboration with his long-time cinematographer Robert Yeoman who rarely gets enough credit for it), RUSHMORE provides early insights into many of the deeper themes and preoccupations that would go on to define Wes Anderson’s work: a focus on class and social status particularly with regards to the hierarchy of positions within esoteric institutions; an eye for the outsider figure and the social outcast; a fascination with under the sea and the life aquatic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonor Will Never Die (Ang Pagbabalik ng Kwago) (2022) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/leonor_will_never_die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/leonor_will_never_die/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic mix of the dramas of the ‘10s combined with the exploitation films of the ‘70s. There is constant surprise in how layered and postmodern the film is willing to get but it always keeps a sense of playfulness and joy in its use of ‘70s exploitation tropes and metafictional devices right up until the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consecration (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</guid>
      <description>A competently-produced Catholic horror film drawing on THE OMEN, THE WICKER MAN, and THE SHINING. There’s a kernel of an interesting idea at the core of the narrative but the script needed at least one more draft and perhaps would have benefitted from leaning into schlocky rather than self-serious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Causes Coughing (Fumer fait tousser) (2022) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</guid>
      <description>The superhero movie that Marvel won’t provide: well-lit, practical effects, strongly defined character relationships and romantic entanglements. Seemingly a commentary on a film market saturated with superhero movies: it feels like Quentin Dupieux had to make a superhero movie because nothing else gets made these days and it was the only way he could tell his absurdist stories about fish concerned with water pollution, a helmet that traps you in your thoughts, and a liquified human’s remains in a bucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Blow Up a Pipeline (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>When I hear motorists and politicians complain about Extinction Rebellion or Just Stop Oil blocking roads, I think they ought to be thankful that the activists are engaging in such milquetoast actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ordinaries (2022) - 120 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</guid>
      <description>THE ORDINARIES’ main character, Paula Feinmann (Fine Sendel), is a Supporting Character. Her father was a Main Character and she studies at the Main Character School to learn how to emote and how to draw the narrative’s attention to herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl (2023) - 87 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</guid>
      <description>Trapped in the intersection of mental health issues, trauma-induced anxiety, and contemporary Scottish racism, Grace (Déborah Lukumuena) seeks to insulate her and her daughter Ama (Le’Shantey Bonsu) against the world outside their high-rise flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polite Society (2023) - 103 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</guid>
      <description>This year’s EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE: a joyous and hilarious blend of genres that uses irony and maximalist extravagance to speak sincerely about specific lived experience but in a universal way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Talking (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/women_talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/women_talking/</guid>
      <description>An adaptation less confident in its source material might have focused on what comes before and what happens after but WOMEN TALKING focuses in on the crux, the critical moments of decision that determine the fate of these women, their community, their families, and their religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the Beauty and the Bloodshed (2022) - 121 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/all_the_beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/all_the_beauty/</guid>
      <description>An exploration not just of the Sackler family and their role in the opioid crisis and the art world but of how alternative communities live, thrive, and survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enys Men (2022) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/enys_men/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/enys_men/</guid>
      <description>A 1970s BBC British horror that has fallen through time to be released in 2023. The Volunteer (Mary Woodvine) undertakes the same ritual each and every day and it gradually becomes clear that she’s not a botanist but something deeper—something older—and that the flower she’s protecting is something more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rashomon (羅生門) (1950) - 88 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rashomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rashomon/</guid>
      <description>A post-apocalyptic period piece filmed in the context of the nuclear annihilation of two cities and 220,000 people, RASHOMON strips down humanity until it finds cynicism, deceit, selfishness, and despair.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
