<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Missed-Part-of-It on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/missed-part-of-it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Missed-Part-of-It on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/missed-part-of-it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Cupcakes (2018) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/christmas_cupcakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/christmas_cupcakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;X xxxxxxxxxxx xxxxxxx &amp;lsquo;xxxxx xxxxxxxx xx xxxxxxx&amp;rsquo; Xxxxxxxxx xxxx xxxx xxxxxxx xxxxxxxxxxxx xxx x xxxxxx lack of background music in scenes where you’d expect it. But then! The second half injects genuine energy through Kristian Bruun’s (queer-coded?) villainous artisan baker and, most significantly, through Greg Lawson channelling Ricardo Montalbán at his most scenery-chewing in his role as Chef Paolo Joeljinjo, an enigmatic but strangely compelling judge of a local TV baking competition show. Lawson’s performance alone saves the film and honestly made me glad we didn’t turn the film off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Very English Christmas (Christmas in the Cotswolds) (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_very_english_christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_very_english_christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xxxxx&amp;rsquo;x x xxxxxxxxxx xxxx xx xx made that A VERY ENGLISH CHRISTMAS is a psychological reflection of the main character’s narcissism in how it moves hollow characters around on the chessboard of the narrative with no regard for their feelings or interiority. Kate’s (Kimberley Nixon) American mother is brought over to England from California at one day’s notice for the wedding of her ex-husband’s daughter and the mother is blankly accepting of this: she doesn’t even get a scene with her ex-husband to say ‘hello’ let alone acknowledge complex feelings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Christmas Exchange (2020) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_christmas_exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_christmas_exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xxxx xxx xxxxx Xxxxxxxx xxxxxxx xx xxxx xxxx, xxxx xxx xxxxxxxxxxxxx xxxxxx xx Xxxxxx. Xxxxxxxxxxxx xxxxxxx xxx xxx xxxxxxxxxxxx xxxxx of ‘London’ use stock footage of Glasgow streets and Glasgow buildings specifically around George Square and Merchant City. This is the kind of detail that might be lost on anyone but an amateur film critic like me who has lived in both London and Glasgow and is why you should commission me for your publication. The film itself is bland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
