<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TAKE-ONE on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/take-one/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TAKE-ONE on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/take-one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mr. K (2024) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mr_k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mr_k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The premise of becoming lost in an infinite hotel filled with eccentric inhabitants with clear inspiration from Kafka, BARTON FINK, &lt;em&gt;House of Leaves&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland&lt;/em&gt; sounded like catnip to me. Disappointingly there’s not much more substance to MR. K beneath the web of allusions and references. There’s a terrifically blank performance from Crispin Glover playing the straight man and some terrific Jeunet and Andersson inspired production design and visual style but it doesn’t add up to much. A wonderfully strange and cosmic ending went some way to redeeming the whole however.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stealing Pulp Fiction (2024) - 78 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stealing_pulp_fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stealing_pulp_fiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That rarest of things for me: a legitimately funny comedy movie. There’s just the right balance of snappy dialogue, colourful characters, postmodern references, and absurdism. In expanding from his original short film, Danny Turkiewicz wisely recognises that this comedy doesn’t need the addition of big emotional arcs but just needs to be more. All you need to know is that it made me laugh after a busy day and one Jason Alexander bit about pickles had me crying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La chimera (2023) - 133 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/la_chimera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/la_chimera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LA CHIMERA has an odd tempo, like a half-remembered story from long ago that becomes clearer when there’s a little rhyme to help you along. Arthur (Josh O’Connor) is a rogue archaeologist, robbing graves and raiding Etruscan tombs. His quasi-mystic gift for finding lost things through a weird dowsing ritual gives the film a mythic quality, rich with allegory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lousy Carter (2023) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lousy_carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lousy_carter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lousy Carter (David Krumholtz) is dying and Bob Byington’s film invites us to ask, who cares? On paper, he’s an unlikeable American literature professor, a narcissist with few friends who halfheartedly pursues a relationship with a student. But David Krumholtz brings him to life with a genuine humanism and dry charm. It’s a comedy that is wonderfully ambivalent about its own existence with the ultimate joke being that, despite openly hating itself, an audience can watch it and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vourdalak (Le Vourdalak) (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_vourdalak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_vourdalak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Though a little off-putting, there’s something charming about the vourdalak puppet who looks something like a Jan Švankmajer creation crossed with one of Mike Mignola’s skeletons from &lt;em&gt;Hellboy in Hell&lt;/em&gt;. This strange puppet takes you out of the film but in a way that is at least interesting to look at and charmingly analogue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tummy Monster (2023) - 85 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tummy_monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tummy_monster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rub your tummy or I’ll think you’re an asshole. UNCUT GEMS in Glasgow: a tense, strange, and frequently hilarious psychological drama that gradually turns a ridiculous situation into the cosmic metaphysical horror of painful and anxious rebirth. Lorn Macdonald and Orlando Norman deliver terrific performances respectively as a hot mess of a tattoo artist and an anonymous popstar turned trickster god. It’s a wholly unexpected delight and a spectacularly confident debut feature from director Ciaran Lyons. Rub your tummy or I’ll think you’re an asshole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Burning Season (2023) - 89 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_burning_season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_burning_season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A love story told backwards taking us from the devastating impact of a couple’s long-running emotional affair to the tragedy that cemented their lives together in the first place. THE BURNING SEASON joins a long lineage of media that &lt;a href=&#34;https://hcommons.org/deposits/item/hc:56781&#34;&gt;I’ve discussed extensively elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; where trauma is represented through the depiction of non-linear time, through time warping around a traumatic event and pulling the characters back towards it like a black hole. A slight romantic drama made effective by some convincingly couple-y dialogue and performances that ground the central relationship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saltburn (2023) - 131 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saltburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saltburn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emerald Fennell follows up her debut with another black comedy dealing with a vector of privilege: this time, the British class system. However the satirising of the upper class never feels as precisely incisive as PROMISING YOUNG WOMAN’s examination of abusive men and “nice guys”. There’s a funny visual gag involving Harry Potter but the portrayal of the upper class family too often pivots into caricature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asteroid City (2023) - 105 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ASTEROID CITY serves as something of an artistic statement for this period of Wes Anderson’s filmmaking, overtly discussing existential themes around meaning and, in particular, finding meaning through art that emphasise Anderson’s complicating of modernism and postmodernism. When Adrien Brody’s director character says that the meaning doesn’t matter, he’s talking through the fourth wall to viewers alienated by Anderson’s idiosyncratic aesthetics. ASTEROID CITY tells the viewer not only how to read it but how to read all of Anderson’s work by openly stating that how the viewer approaches his films is critical to how the works produce sincerity with and through their ironic postmodern conceits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Causes Coughing (Fumer fait tousser) (2022) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The superhero movie that Marvel won’t provide: well-lit, practical effects, strongly defined character relationships and romantic entanglements. Seemingly a commentary on a film market saturated with superhero movies: it feels like Quentin Dupieux had to make a superhero movie because nothing else gets made these days and it was the only way he could tell his absurdist stories about fish concerned with water pollution, a helmet that traps you in your thoughts, and a liquified human’s remains in a bucket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary (2022) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SANCTUARY’s thoughtful depiction of fetish uses the sense of mystery behind sub-dom to bring the audience into the characters’ tangled power dynamics. You’re made part of the role-play because you, like the characters, don’t know what is real and what is erotic play. This wouldn’t work if the film didn’t also make you want Margaret Qualley to step on you. Her expressive face conveys what is otherwise left unsaid while also hiding secrets behind the role-play. The power of her role is in making you fall in love with her while basically learning nothing about her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Blow Up a Pipeline (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I hear motorists and politicians complain about Extinction Rebellion or Just Stop Oil blocking roads, I think they ought to be thankful that the activists are engaging in such milquetoast actions. In a just world, their SUVs would be destroyed, fossil fuel extraction and refinement facilities would be expropriated and dismantled, and private planes would be permanently grounded. As Andreas Malm argues in the book that inspires this film, property destruction and sabotage are more than justified at this stage in the climate crisis. A few well-placed drone attacks on the private planes of the most obscenely wealthy and destructive could do wonders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ordinaries (2022) - 120 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE ORDINARIES’ main character, Paula Feinmann (Fine Sendel), is a Supporting Character. Her father was a Main Character and she studies at the Main Character School to learn how to emote and how to draw the narrative’s attention to herself. It’s a meta conceit that pushes against the limits of cinematic structure in a way similar to Spike Jonze’s ADAPTATION or Charlie Kaufman’s SYNECDOCHE, NEW YORK. Like Davey Wreden’s The Stanley Parable, the entire film is a metacommentary where the tension comes from the threat of the narrative collapsing under its own postmodern convolutions. THE ORDINARIES is successful inasmuch as it doesn’t collapse and says something about class and emotional expression even if the pacing falls off towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Typist Artist Pirate King (2022) - 106 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An England seen through the prism of mental illness might be the truest view of England. TYPIST ARTIST PIRATE KING takes the audience on a psychogeographic journey along the length of England through the eyes of Audrey Amiss (Monica Dolan), a mentally ill British artist whose work was only recognised after her death in 2013. Audrey describes herself as “avant-garde and misunderstood”, a perpetual victim let down by society and those around her. Like TÁR, the world of the film is a reflection of the protagonist’s mental state and we see an England without stability, an England replete with abandoned hospitals and Viking battles and Morris dancers in the street and low-simmering resentments against perceived enemies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Artist and the Wall of Death (2022) - 86 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A documentary about the theme of failure that abdicates its responsibility to discuss the actual human costs of failure. Stephen Skrynka is a visual artist obsessed with the Wall of Death, a fairground stunt attraction inside which a motorcyclist drives around the walls of a wooden cylinder. Though the documentary focuses on superficial surface level failures—Stephen falling off motorcycles and injuring himself—it fails to adequately explore the emotional and financial costs of the larger failures to the people he’s enlisted to help him achieve his dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polite Society (2023) - 103 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year’s EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE: a joyous and hilarious blend of genres that uses irony and maximalist extravagance to speak sincerely about specific lived experience but in a universal way. POLITE SOCIETY is a modern Jane Austen story that combines wuxia films like CROUCHING TIGER, HIDDEN DRAGON with comic-book style films like SCOTT PILGRIM VS. THE WORLD all in service of a story that speaks to how modern British-Pakistani women approach practices like arranged marriage and how the generational trauma of second-generation immigrants continues to filter down to their children. Outstanding supporting turns from Ella Bruccoleri, Seraphina Beh, and Nimra Bucha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nightsiren (Svetlonoc) (2022) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Šarlota (Natália Germáni) returns to the mountain village where she grew up to find she’s an object of suspicion to the villagers. The gradual influx of horror elements and the dreamy expressionistic cinematography of the lush European forest are similar to David Bruckner’s THE RITUAL but where that film dealt with manhood and toxic masculinity, NIGHTSIREN centres on womanhood and explores social sexual norms in Eastern Europe. Is Šarlota a witch or an urban, educated, sexually-liberated woman? Proving that folk horror isn’t an exclusively English subgenre, NIGHTSIREN uses folk traditions and symbolism in service of its exploration of the societal misogyny buried just beneath the surface of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Astronaut (L’Astronaute) (2022) - 110 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A charming celebration of the amateur. Jim Desforges (Nicolas Giraud) is an aeronautical engineer who dreams of launching the first amateur manned space flight. Like BRIAN AND CHARLES or A BUNCH OF AMATEURS, there’s a charm in seeing the film’s amateur rocket scientists building a rocket out of scraps in a farmhouse. There’s an accompanying sense of power and liberation too: why should space travel be the province solely of nation states or major corporations? Why couldn’t we open source space travel and open up the Earth’s gravitational prison for anyone and everyone with the will to escape it? A gentle film with a climax that makes the journey worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Therapy Dogs (2022) - 83 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High school is a shared nightmare. A unique subculture that most of us experienced but which we’ve forgotten the intensity of. Ethan Eng’s debut feature captures the anarchic chaos of the high school experience with a dizzying montage of styles, tones, and genres while also representing the deep emotional lows of separating from friends and the feeling that, after high school, life as you know it will be over. Astonishingly inventive Gen Z filmmaking proving the next generation will be better than mine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other People’s Children (Les Enfants des autres) (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE WORST PERSON IN THE WORLD is to thirty-somethings what OTHER PEOPLE’S CHILDREN is to forty-somethings: a mature emotionally resonant romantic comedy-drama that embraces the complexity of modern relationships. Since I’m closer to forty than thirty, I was more affected by this film about a childless adult navigating relationships with other people’s children while conflicted about their own potential for parenthood than the former. It’s honestly refreshing to see a romantic comedy that straightforwardly deals with adulthood, sexuality, and parenthood with far more emotional maturity than any Hollywood romcom. Get the ‘unnecessary sex scene’ discourse people to watch this and have their heads explode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tropic (Tropique) (2022) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cosmic event strikes the lake where two brothers are swimming, mutilating one and dooming his chances of taking part in Europe’s first space colonisation mission. TROPIC is an intriguing blend of genres that talks about humanity and what it means to accept or abandon what cannot be changed. The film has a slow weirdness that evokes Apichatpong Weerasethakul’s MEMORIA and alludes to John Carpenter’s sci-fi horror of the ‘80s. TROPIC presents an interesting metaphor for what space colonisation would mean for the planet but could benefit from tighter editing to resolve some structural issues and a little more time spent on ancillary plotlines to build them up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adopting Audrey (2021) - 92 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a huge generational divide between baby boomers who are rich in capital but emotionally immature and millennials who are poor but emotionally fortified by multiple recessions and 21st century uncertainty. ADOPTING AUDREY examines the gap between the generations and mines what shared emotions can be found there. Jena Malone is terrific as a socially atomised millennial striving for community and a sense of what home might be while Robert Hunger-Bühler is very funny as a cold Herzogian boomer parent who can’t connect with his children despite his growing regrets in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eo (2022) - 86 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EO directed by Jerzy Skolimowski uses the language of cinema to push us to empathise with a non-human protagonist and therefore expand our sense of subjectivity to cover the perspective of its titular donkey. Without dialogue and with an incredible soundscape, EO follows a circus donkey as he encounters other animals and wanders through the ruins and conflicts of modern European history. Like Kossakovsky’s GUNDA and Arnold’s COW, EO pushes us to consider the exploitation of animals and the subjectivity of the others on this planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
