<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cinetopia on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/cinetopia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cinetopia on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/cinetopia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mission: Impossible – Dead Reckoning Part One (2023) - 163 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mission_impossible_dead_reckoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mission_impossible_dead_reckoning/</guid>
      <description>Venice is a ghost town in this movie. Presumably due to Covid restrictions during filming, the city is heartbreakingly empty. Piazza San Marco and Campo della Salute bustle with tourists, even at night, and yet here they have only one or two people milling about as a backdrop for the main characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shabu (2021) - 75 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/shabu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/shabu/</guid>
      <description>An impossible gem of a film. It seems impossible that you can push the form of a documentary so far towards social realist aesthetics and structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The March on Rome (Marcia su Roma) (2022) - 97 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</guid>
      <description>Mark Cousins’ calm matter-of-fact narration doesn’t impose parallels between Italian fascist propaganda of the 1920s and today’s modern fascist propaganda but instead allows the obvious parallels to speak for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saint Omer (2022) - 123 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saint_omer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saint_omer/</guid>
      <description>Quiet devastation erupts in discrete moments of an otherwise drawn-out trial. Alice Diop shows the processes of institutional justice in all their long, slow, and wordy reality with long shots on one person talking, defending herself, and repeating her life story for the court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tár (2022) - 158 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tar/</guid>
      <description>Cate Blanchett plays Lydia Tár as a charming, authoritative, magnetic, and terrible person. We’re fully immersed in the life and perspective of a deeply unpleasant person and there’s a complex catharsis as the film charts her downfall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enys Men (2022) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/enys_men/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/enys_men/</guid>
      <description>A 1970s BBC British horror that has fallen through time to be released in 2023. The Volunteer (Mary Woodvine) undertakes the same ritual each and every day and it gradually becomes clear that she’s not a botanist but something deeper—something older—and that the flower she’s protecting is something more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
