<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GFF2025 on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2025/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GFF2025 on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Peacock (Pfau - Bin ich echt?) (2024) - 102 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/peacock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/peacock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s an interesting but undeveloped metaphor for neurodivergence in PEACOCK (PFAU - BIN ICH ECHT?), a film where Matthias (Albrecht Schuch) spends his entire life masking as part of his job playing various social roles for clients. He masks to such an extent that the person underneath begins to disappear, leading his girlfriend (Julia Franz Richter) to ask the titular question, “Are you real?” The film explores this alongside some other interesting questions around performance, honesty, and humanity but it all feels a little light by the end in a way that feels as if it hasn’t properly engaged with its weighty themes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharp Corner (2024) - 110 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sharp_corner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sharp_corner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An astonishing physical performance from Ben Foster drives this thriller where the villain is not a serial killer but road infrastructure and careless rural driving practices. Ben Foster is a charming, creepy, unreadable quiet little man whose obsession drives away his hot wife (played by Cobie Smulders who manages to do enough with the very little character that the screenplay gives). Foster’s secret seems to be bringing a little Tim Robinson energy to the role in a way that makes the script pop while also tapping into the deep pathos of the character and further establishes &lt;em&gt;I Think You Should Leave&lt;/em&gt; as the key text of our current sociocultural moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Surfer (2024) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_surfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_surfer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s something extra tense about a thriller that could be resolved instantly if the character just did something – anything – different: in this case if Nicolas Cage’s nameless protagonist just left the beach car park where he spends the entire film. Fortunately he doesn’t and director Lorcan Finnegan gives us a trippy take on the classic Cage performance, emphasising the deep psychological distress of this character and his one-man war of attrition against some mean Australians. A wildly entertaining film that portrays the stifling and oppressive atmosphere of a dry heat and the bizarre madness that it induces uncomfortably well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tornado (2025) - 100 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tornado/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tornado/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The howling of the wind around walls and through trees dominates the soundscape of the film’s first half, subtly suggesting the Scottish landscape itself turning against Tornado (Kōki,). However the wind dies down in the second half as Tornado herself takes on the force of the wind and becomes the avenging samurai that the land needs. TORNADO has an incredible sense of place, embedded in the Scottish hills where the film was shot. The space is clearly articulated in the film such that we always have a sense of the geography of the lake around which the story takes place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mr. K (2024) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mr_k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mr_k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The premise of becoming lost in an infinite hotel filled with eccentric inhabitants with clear inspiration from Kafka, BARTON FINK, &lt;em&gt;House of Leaves&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland&lt;/em&gt; sounded like catnip to me. Disappointingly there’s not much more substance to MR. K beneath the web of allusions and references. There’s a terrifically blank performance from Crispin Glover playing the straight man and some terrific Jeunet and Andersson inspired production design and visual style but it doesn’t add up to much. A wonderfully strange and cosmic ending went some way to redeeming the whole however.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homegrown (2024) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/homegrown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/homegrown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was extremely concerned that this documentary on the rise of American neo-fascism would sympathise with the three Proud Boys that it follows but was pleased to see that director Michael Premo’s detached style of documentary filmmaking simply observes the men exposing themselves as mendacious, stupid, incoherent, and selfish without particularly expecting the audience to care about their racist and bigoted concerns. These are men obsessed with their warped ideas of freedom and capitalism who like to indulge in the casual cruelty of threatening to crucify an “Antifa” protester or dumping gallons of paint on Black Lives Matter protesters. Living in 2025, it unfortunately feels like half a story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stealing Pulp Fiction (2024) - 78 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stealing_pulp_fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stealing_pulp_fiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That rarest of things for me: a legitimately funny comedy movie. There’s just the right balance of snappy dialogue, colourful characters, postmodern references, and absurdism. In expanding from his original short film, Danny Turkiewicz wisely recognises that this comedy doesn’t need the addition of big emotional arcs but just needs to be more. All you need to know is that it made me laugh after a busy day and one Jason Alexander bit about pickles had me crying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
