<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GFF2023 on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GFF2023 on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consecration (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A competently-produced Catholic horror film drawing on THE OMEN, THE WICKER MAN, and THE SHINING. There’s a kernel of an interesting idea at the core of the narrative but the script needed at least one more draft and perhaps would have benefitted from leaning into schlocky rather than self-serious. There’s some stunning cinematography benefitting from the natural drama of Skye’s landscape and the use of Christian, specifically Catholic, imagery deepens the film with the weight of Christianity’s inherent horror but it doesn’t feel like it adds up to very much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Causes Coughing (Fumer fait tousser) (2022) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The superhero movie that Marvel won’t provide: well-lit, practical effects, strongly defined character relationships and romantic entanglements. Seemingly a commentary on a film market saturated with superhero movies: it feels like Quentin Dupieux had to make a superhero movie because nothing else gets made these days and it was the only way he could tell his absurdist stories about fish concerned with water pollution, a helmet that traps you in your thoughts, and a liquified human’s remains in a bucket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The March on Rome (Marcia su Roma) (2022) - 97 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Cousins’ calm matter-of-fact narration doesn’t impose parallels between Italian fascist propaganda of the 1920s and today’s modern fascist propaganda but instead allows the obvious parallels to speak for themselves. Like Claude Lanzmann, Cousins damns fascists—Trump, Bolsonaro, Le Pen, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/commentisfree/2021/oct/23/judith-butler-gender-ideology-backlash&#34;&gt;the UK’s transphobic movement&lt;/a&gt;—by showing the words they have actually said. There’s more than a little liberal equivocation and naïvety in asking what should be done with relics of fascist heritage but the methodical close reading of films like A NOI! (1922, dir. Umberto Paradisi) drew me in as a great example of reading politics from cinema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Father, The Devil (Mon Père, Le Diable) (2021) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/our_father_the_devil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/our_father_the_devil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ellie Foumbi’s debut feature makes terrific use of light and shadow for its story of trauma, revenge, and forgiveness. Marie (Babetida Sadjo) is haunted by her past trauma and sees it in the face of the new priest, Father Patrick (Souleymane Sy Savane). Father Patrick’s face is hidden for his first few scenes and even after it’s revealed, his face is often shrouded in shadow or emerging out of darkness cultivating an air of menace even as he protests his innocence of the crimes against Marie. As things spiral out of control, it’s Marie’s face that increasingly gets shrouded in darkness as we question whose account is true.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Like Movies (2022) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/i_like_movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/i_like_movies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Enjoyable as a sweet throw-back to quirky indie comedies of the ‘00s: a little NAPOLEON DYNAMITE and a dash of Kevin Smith. Honestly it would work better if I hadn’t seen it at the same festival as &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/&#34;&gt;THERAPY DOGS&lt;/a&gt; because the two bear immediate comparison and I LIKE MOVIES comes out worse: both involve aspiring filmmakers in a Canadian high school who are putting together a year-end video and who have an emotional conflict with their one friend and filmmaking partner. I LIKE MOVIES is the parallel universe THERAPY DOGS where it was made as a traditional filmic interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary (2022) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SANCTUARY’s thoughtful depiction of fetish uses the sense of mystery behind sub-dom to bring the audience into the characters’ tangled power dynamics. You’re made part of the role-play because you, like the characters, don’t know what is real and what is erotic play. This wouldn’t work if the film didn’t also make you want Margaret Qualley to step on you. Her expressive face conveys what is otherwise left unsaid while also hiding secrets behind the role-play. The power of her role is in making you fall in love with her while basically learning nothing about her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stone Turtle (2022) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stone_turtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stone_turtle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mix of THE WICKER MAN and GROUNDHOG DAY that is an interesting blend of genres but adds up to less than the sum of its parts. A community of women refugees living on a small island are treated as non-citizens by the wider world; they are ghosts in the land of the living. Their fragile existence is disrupted when male violence encroaches on their island. STONE TURTLE has a beautifully animated and heartbreaking &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N-OeCYaZgT4&#34;&gt;eye-of-the-duck&lt;/a&gt; scene that evokes THE RED TURTLE and holds the key to unlocking the whole film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Under the Skin (2013) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/under_the_skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/under_the_skin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An English woman struggles to find the M8 and gradually learns to see Scottish people as human beings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best representations of the alien and unknown use abstract visual poetry to represent the alien as not only unknown and unknowable but literally inconceivable to us within the bounds that we think in. UNDER THE SKIN excels at this from the opening moments immersing us in eerie conceptual imagery and Mica Levi’s otherworldly but menacing score. I’d never noticed before but there’s slightly disjointed editing in her early interactions with the random Glaswegian men she picks up and it really contributes to the unmoored feeling of that first half.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Blow Up a Pipeline (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I hear motorists and politicians complain about Extinction Rebellion or Just Stop Oil blocking roads, I think they ought to be thankful that the activists are engaging in such milquetoast actions. In a just world, their SUVs would be destroyed, fossil fuel extraction and refinement facilities would be expropriated and dismantled, and private planes would be permanently grounded. As Andreas Malm argues in the book that inspires this film, property destruction and sabotage are more than justified at this stage in the climate crisis. A few well-placed drone attacks on the private planes of the most obscenely wealthy and destructive could do wonders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ordinaries (2022) - 120 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE ORDINARIES’ main character, Paula Feinmann (Fine Sendel), is a Supporting Character. Her father was a Main Character and she studies at the Main Character School to learn how to emote and how to draw the narrative’s attention to herself. It’s a meta conceit that pushes against the limits of cinematic structure in a way similar to Spike Jonze’s ADAPTATION or Charlie Kaufman’s SYNECDOCHE, NEW YORK. Like Davey Wreden’s The Stanley Parable, the entire film is a metacommentary where the tension comes from the threat of the narrative collapsing under its own postmodern convolutions. THE ORDINARIES is successful inasmuch as it doesn’t collapse and says something about class and emotional expression even if the pacing falls off towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Typist Artist Pirate King (2022) - 106 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An England seen through the prism of mental illness might be the truest view of England. TYPIST ARTIST PIRATE KING takes the audience on a psychogeographic journey along the length of England through the eyes of Audrey Amiss (Monica Dolan), a mentally ill British artist whose work was only recognised after her death in 2013. Audrey describes herself as “avant-garde and misunderstood”, a perpetual victim let down by society and those around her. Like TÁR, the world of the film is a reflection of the protagonist’s mental state and we see an England without stability, an England replete with abandoned hospitals and Viking battles and Morris dancers in the street and low-simmering resentments against perceived enemies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Artist and the Wall of Death (2022) - 86 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A documentary about the theme of failure that abdicates its responsibility to discuss the actual human costs of failure. Stephen Skrynka is a visual artist obsessed with the Wall of Death, a fairground stunt attraction inside which a motorcyclist drives around the walls of a wooden cylinder. Though the documentary focuses on superficial surface level failures—Stephen falling off motorcycles and injuring himself—it fails to adequately explore the emotional and financial costs of the larger failures to the people he’s enlisted to help him achieve his dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girl (2023) - 87 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trapped in the intersection of mental health issues, trauma-induced anxiety, and contemporary Scottish racism, Grace (Déborah Lukumuena) seeks to insulate her and her daughter Ama (Le’Shantey Bonsu) against the world outside their high-rise flat. Ama seeks a world beyond her mother. A tough watch partly because Lukumuena’s striking performance was triggeringly accurate for me in her depiction of panic attacks. A beautiful film that shows an unbeautiful world: the lighting of Black skin was particularly impressive and effective in letting the actors express themselves through subtle gestures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polite Society (2023) - 103 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year’s EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE: a joyous and hilarious blend of genres that uses irony and maximalist extravagance to speak sincerely about specific lived experience but in a universal way. POLITE SOCIETY is a modern Jane Austen story that combines wuxia films like CROUCHING TIGER, HIDDEN DRAGON with comic-book style films like SCOTT PILGRIM VS. THE WORLD all in service of a story that speaks to how modern British-Pakistani women approach practices like arranged marriage and how the generational trauma of second-generation immigrants continues to filter down to their children. Outstanding supporting turns from Ella Bruccoleri, Seraphina Beh, and Nimra Bucha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nightsiren (Svetlonoc) (2022) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Šarlota (Natália Germáni) returns to the mountain village where she grew up to find she’s an object of suspicion to the villagers. The gradual influx of horror elements and the dreamy expressionistic cinematography of the lush European forest are similar to David Bruckner’s THE RITUAL but where that film dealt with manhood and toxic masculinity, NIGHTSIREN centres on womanhood and explores social sexual norms in Eastern Europe. Is Šarlota a witch or an urban, educated, sexually-liberated woman? Proving that folk horror isn’t an exclusively English subgenre, NIGHTSIREN uses folk traditions and symbolism in service of its exploration of the societal misogyny buried just beneath the surface of everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Astronaut (L’Astronaute) (2022) - 110 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A charming celebration of the amateur. Jim Desforges (Nicolas Giraud) is an aeronautical engineer who dreams of launching the first amateur manned space flight. Like BRIAN AND CHARLES or A BUNCH OF AMATEURS, there’s a charm in seeing the film’s amateur rocket scientists building a rocket out of scraps in a farmhouse. There’s an accompanying sense of power and liberation too: why should space travel be the province solely of nation states or major corporations? Why couldn’t we open source space travel and open up the Earth’s gravitational prison for anyone and everyone with the will to escape it? A gentle film with a climax that makes the journey worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Therapy Dogs (2022) - 83 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High school is a shared nightmare. A unique subculture that most of us experienced but which we’ve forgotten the intensity of. Ethan Eng’s debut feature captures the anarchic chaos of the high school experience with a dizzying montage of styles, tones, and genres while also representing the deep emotional lows of separating from friends and the feeling that, after high school, life as you know it will be over. Astonishingly inventive Gen Z filmmaking proving the next generation will be better than mine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other People’s Children (Les Enfants des autres) (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE WORST PERSON IN THE WORLD is to thirty-somethings what OTHER PEOPLE’S CHILDREN is to forty-somethings: a mature emotionally resonant romantic comedy-drama that embraces the complexity of modern relationships. Since I’m closer to forty than thirty, I was more affected by this film about a childless adult navigating relationships with other people’s children while conflicted about their own potential for parenthood than the former. It’s honestly refreshing to see a romantic comedy that straightforwardly deals with adulthood, sexuality, and parenthood with far more emotional maturity than any Hollywood romcom. Get the ‘unnecessary sex scene’ discourse people to watch this and have their heads explode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tropic (Tropique) (2022) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cosmic event strikes the lake where two brothers are swimming, mutilating one and dooming his chances of taking part in Europe’s first space colonisation mission. TROPIC is an intriguing blend of genres that talks about humanity and what it means to accept or abandon what cannot be changed. The film has a slow weirdness that evokes Apichatpong Weerasethakul’s MEMORIA and alludes to John Carpenter’s sci-fi horror of the ‘80s. TROPIC presents an interesting metaphor for what space colonisation would mean for the planet but could benefit from tighter editing to resolve some structural issues and a little more time spent on ancillary plotlines to build them up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adopting Audrey (2021) - 92 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a huge generational divide between baby boomers who are rich in capital but emotionally immature and millennials who are poor but emotionally fortified by multiple recessions and 21st century uncertainty. ADOPTING AUDREY examines the gap between the generations and mines what shared emotions can be found there. Jena Malone is terrific as a socially atomised millennial striving for community and a sense of what home might be while Robert Hunger-Bühler is very funny as a cold Herzogian boomer parent who can’t connect with his children despite his growing regrets in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
