<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GFF2023 on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GFF2023 on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consecration (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</guid>
      <description>A competently-produced Catholic horror film drawing on THE OMEN, THE WICKER MAN, and THE SHINING. There’s a kernel of an interesting idea at the core of the narrative but the script needed at least one more draft and perhaps would have benefitted from leaning into schlocky rather than self-serious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Causes Coughing (Fumer fait tousser) (2022) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/smoking_causes_coughing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/smoking_causes_coughing/</guid>
      <description>The superhero movie that Marvel won’t provide: well-lit, practical effects, strongly defined character relationships and romantic entanglements. Seemingly a commentary on a film market saturated with superhero movies: it feels like Quentin Dupieux had to make a superhero movie because nothing else gets made these days and it was the only way he could tell his absurdist stories about fish concerned with water pollution, a helmet that traps you in your thoughts, and a liquified human’s remains in a bucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The March on Rome (Marcia su Roma) (2022) - 97 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</guid>
      <description>Mark Cousins’ calm matter-of-fact narration doesn’t impose parallels between Italian fascist propaganda of the 1920s and today’s modern fascist propaganda but instead allows the obvious parallels to speak for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Father, The Devil (Mon Père, Le Diable) (2021) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/our_father_the_devil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/our_father_the_devil/</guid>
      <description>Ellie Foumbi’s debut feature makes terrific use of light and shadow for its story of trauma, revenge, and forgiveness. Marie (Babetida Sadjo) is haunted by her past trauma and sees it in the face of the new priest, Father Patrick (Souleymane Sy Savane).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Like Movies (2022) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/i_like_movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/i_like_movies/</guid>
      <description>Enjoyable as a sweet throw-back to quirky indie comedies of the ‘00s: a little NAPOLEON DYNAMITE and a dash of Kevin Smith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary (2022) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</guid>
      <description>SANCTUARY’s thoughtful depiction of fetish uses the sense of mystery behind sub-dom to bring the audience into the characters’ tangled power dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stone Turtle (2022) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stone_turtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stone_turtle/</guid>
      <description>A mix of THE WICKER MAN and GROUNDHOG DAY that is an interesting blend of genres but adds up to less than the sum of its parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the Skin (2013) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/under_the_skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/under_the_skin/</guid>
      <description>An English woman struggles to find the M8 and gradually learns to see Scottish people as human beings.
The best representations of the alien and unknown use abstract visual poetry to represent the alien as not only unknown and unknowable but literally inconceivable to us within the bounds that we think in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Blow Up a Pipeline (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>When I hear motorists and politicians complain about Extinction Rebellion or Just Stop Oil blocking roads, I think they ought to be thankful that the activists are engaging in such milquetoast actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ordinaries (2022) - 120 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</guid>
      <description>THE ORDINARIES’ main character, Paula Feinmann (Fine Sendel), is a Supporting Character. Her father was a Main Character and she studies at the Main Character School to learn how to emote and how to draw the narrative’s attention to herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typist Artist Pirate King (2022) - 106 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</guid>
      <description>An England seen through the prism of mental illness might be the truest view of England. TYPIST ARTIST PIRATE KING takes the audience on a psychogeographic journey along the length of England through the eyes of Audrey Amiss (Monica Dolan), a mentally ill British artist whose work was only recognised after her death in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Artist and the Wall of Death (2022) - 86 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</guid>
      <description>A documentary about the theme of failure that abdicates its responsibility to discuss the actual human costs of failure. Stephen Skrynka is a visual artist obsessed with the Wall of Death, a fairground stunt attraction inside which a motorcyclist drives around the walls of a wooden cylinder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl (2023) - 87 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</guid>
      <description>Trapped in the intersection of mental health issues, trauma-induced anxiety, and contemporary Scottish racism, Grace (Déborah Lukumuena) seeks to insulate her and her daughter Ama (Le’Shantey Bonsu) against the world outside their high-rise flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polite Society (2023) - 103 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</guid>
      <description>This year’s EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE: a joyous and hilarious blend of genres that uses irony and maximalist extravagance to speak sincerely about specific lived experience but in a universal way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightsiren (Svetlonoc) (2022) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</guid>
      <description>Šarlota (Natália Germáni) returns to the mountain village where she grew up to find she’s an object of suspicion to the villagers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Astronaut (L’Astronaute) (2022) - 110 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</guid>
      <description>A charming celebration of the amateur. Jim Desforges (Nicolas Giraud) is an aeronautical engineer who dreams of launching the first amateur manned space flight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapy Dogs (2022) - 83 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</guid>
      <description>High school is a shared nightmare. A unique subculture that most of us experienced but which we’ve forgotten the intensity of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other People’s Children (Les Enfants des autres) (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</guid>
      <description>THE WORST PERSON IN THE WORLD is to thirty-somethings what OTHER PEOPLE’S CHILDREN is to forty-somethings: a mature emotionally resonant romantic comedy-drama that embraces the complexity of modern relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropic (Tropique) (2022) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic event strikes the lake where two brothers are swimming, mutilating one and dooming his chances of taking part in Europe’s first space colonisation mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adopting Audrey (2021) - 92 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</guid>
      <description>There’s a huge generational divide between baby boomers who are rich in capital but emotionally immature and millennials who are poor but emotionally fortified by multiple recessions and 21st century uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
