<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steven-Spielberg on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/steven-spielberg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Steven-Spielberg on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/steven-spielberg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Fabelmans (2022) - 151 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_fabelmans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_fabelmans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Martin Scorsese’s HUGO and Steven Spielberg’s THE FABELMANS would make a fascinating double-bil: one showing an artist in his late period exteriorising his love of cinema and the other interiorising it. Though THE FABELMANS starts a little saccharine for my tastes, the film matures along with Sammy Fabelman (Gabriel LaBelle) and goes on the same psychological journey from the naïve depiction of film as a medium for discovery of truth in the world to exploring how a director shapes reality through documentary editing and makes an active choice as to how their film portrays people and the world. The most poignant moments are where Spielberg reaches through the screen to point out to us how the pursuit of art has mediated the experience of his life for good—the final camera tilt—and ill—Sammy seeing himself in the mirror filming his parents’ divorce. David Lynch playing the greatest living filmmaker is meta perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Munich (2005) - 164 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/munich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/munich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Steven Spielberg adopts the tropes and tone of John le Carré novels and Cold War thriller films and contorts them to fit a conflict with a wildly different power differential. As the film develops, the violence of the Israeli-sanctioned assassins expands in scope ultimately turning into a grotesque numbers game with Hans (Hanns Zischler) reeling off numbers of terrorist atrocities and deaths as if that can justify their state power’s campaign of ‘righteous’ revenge. The dialogue of violence becomes more and more one-sided and Spielberg doesn’t flinch from showing how broken, mad, and hollow that violence makes a person. The absence of Palestinian voices from the film is unfortunate but speaks to Spielberg’s understandable personal focus which is how Israel’s perpetual avenging violence drives a wedge between Jewish people and the nation they can no longer call ‘home’. The final shot of the World Trade Center dates the film as firmly early-’00s but emphasises the overall sense of despair at the prospect of peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jurassic Park (1993) - 127 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/jurassic_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/jurassic_park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A film with incredible depth of detail. On the big screen for the 30th anniversary, I caught so many small background details in almost every frame that catch the eye but aren’t visually overwhelming and make the world feel lived in. There are subtle character moments peppered throughout the screenplay that quietly expand the characters (despite abundant places for a helipad across the island, Hammond has deliberately placed it in a valley with wind shears so that it’s next to an amazing waterfall underscoring his prioritisation of spectacle over safety). Seeing it in the cinema, I was struck by the sound: the subtle ‘80s-style synth in the opening’s score and the incredible sound design of all the various dinosaurs’ different calls, especially the T. rex and velociraptors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade (1989) - 127 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/last_crusade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/last_crusade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days, a huge amount of money would be spent on special effects to make the boat chase actually look like it’s taking place in Venice. Steven Spielberg correctly intuits that it’s enough for an audience to watch boats going fast and makes no attempt to disguise the dockyard (presumably in California) where it’s actually filmed. Such is the strength of Sean Connery’s performance as Henry Jones Sr. that as a kid I thought every third film in a series should introduce the main character’s parents. Perhaps one too many action scenes for me these days but the three trials before the Grail are really tense and masterfully edited. Spielberg is such a safe pair of hands as a blockbuster director that it’s a real comfort watch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
