<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The-Xenopod on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/the-xenopod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The-Xenopod on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/the-xenopod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alien: Covenant (2017) - 122 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_covenant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_covenant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A best-of of the Alien franchise that brings together the best elements of the series but never manages to resolve the franchise’s long-running identity crisis. Though &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@SimonXIX/alien-covenant-removing-the-alien-from-alien-a02b32ee6911&#34;&gt;I hated this when it came out&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve softened on it a lot and think it works well at building slow-burn tension, developing interesting characters, and pursuing some resonant themes around colonialism, imperialism, and genocide, creation and destruction, and fascism’s pursuit of imagined purity. However it falls down in its attempts to link to the other films in the franchise particularly &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/prometheus/&#34;&gt;PROMETHEUS&lt;/a&gt; and ALIEN and its position in the franchise canon as an explanation of the Xenomorphs’ origins is a fundamentally misguided and self-defeating endeavour. Better than I remembered but a film that should not exist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus (2012) - 124 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/prometheus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A grand, sweeping science-fiction spectacle that is utterly hampered by the script’s atrocious dialogue, clunky exposition, weird pacing, and scientist characters that never act like scientists. It’s as if Jon Spaihts’ original script for Alien: Engineers were run through a machine-learning tool which inserted as many of Damon Lindelof’s late-’00s to early-’10s writing quirks and thematic obsessions as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aliens vs. Predator: Requiem (2007) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aliens_vs_predator_requiem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aliens_vs_predator_requiem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A prurient and nasty film with deeply conservative undercurrents. REQUIEM not only cannot comprehend the anti-capitalist message of the original ALIEN but transforms the (sub-)franchise into something horribly regressive in service of cutting the Xenomorph down into a monster from a generic slasher movie and symbolically punishing the people on the lowest rungs of neoliberal society. Though the film is often too dark to see the actual scenes, what we can see in this film are embryonic traces of the franchise blockbuster model which will soon come to dominate 21st Century Hollywood filmmaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alien vs. Predator (2004) - 101 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_vs_predator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_vs_predator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for &lt;a href=&#34;https://takeonecinema.net/thexenopod/&#34;&gt;our podcast&lt;/a&gt;, it’s more interesting to discuss this film than it is to watch it. The film itself is bland and generic with paper-thin characters, a frankly unappealing visual aesthetic, and dialogue that could have been spat out by a machine-learning model. But it represents a fascinating point for the Alien franchise’s turn from a multimedia to a transmedia franchise and occupies a contested position as both mothership text and paratext. There’s also an intriguing path not taken with the Black female main character and the shooting script’s promise that she will return in the unmade Alien/Predator: Annihilation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alien Resurrection (1997) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_resurrection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_resurrection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of the film, the Newborn is violently sucked through a tiny hole into Earth’s upper atmosphere. This film feels like trying to suck the Alien franchise through a much-diminished perspective to become a generic and misogynistic blockbuster. Most of the blame must lie with Whedon’s script which firmly shifts the sexual locus of the franchise from ALIEN’s ‘monstrous feminine’ to the most mundane implementation of male gaze from the perspective of a teenage boy. Ripley’s new ‘sexy but threatening’ persona completely disregards what worked about the character in the previous films. A script that doesn’t work with a director who does not fit the Alien franchise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alien³ (1992) - 114 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Fincher gets a lot better and a lot more subtle at hiding his disdain for his films’ ‘airport bestseller’ source material. In ALIEN³, he barely disguises his contempt for James Cameron’s ALIENS and we end up with this film’s identity crisis as the narrative is pulled between the horns of ALIEN and ALIENS while tackling heady themes that the film’s grotesque mishmash of a script cannot support. A strong first half sets up some interesting ideas around religious oppression and redemption, toxic masculinity and Christian fundamentalism, and nihilism and suicidal ideation that all collapse in the second half as a shonky action-scene-by-committee extends interminably. A disappointment that collapses under its own thematic weight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aliens (1986) - 137 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aliens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aliens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After ALIEN, ALIENS put the franchise on a path that it didn’t have to take. There was a path available where ALIEN 2 continues with the New Hollywood feel of ALIEN, where it explores the mysterious cosmic Lovecraftian horror of LV-426 and the alien creature, where it leans into the elements that made ALIEN such a masterpiece. Instead, like STAR TREK II: THE WRATH OF KHAN, ALIENS pulls the blossoming franchise into the black hole of blockbuster action films and starts what my co-host Jim Ross refers to as the franchise’s ongoing identity crisis. ALIENS is a very good action movie: solid production design, a terrific screenplay (apart from some corny James Cameron dialogue), and great performances across the board. But I mourn for the ALIEN sequels that we never got because of what this film is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
