<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>film on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in film on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moonrise Kingdom (2012) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/moonrise_kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/moonrise_kingdom/</guid>
      <description>In an essay for the Criterion Collection Blu-ray, Isabel Folger writes that “Moonrise Kingdom shows that with the right people in your life, you won’t feel misunderstood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life Aquatic with Steve Zissou (2004) - 119 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_life_aquatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_life_aquatic/</guid>
      <description>The Titan submersible incident prompted a response by James Cameron highlighting his approach to underwater exploration. I’m struck by the contrast between Wes Anderson’s almost childlike reverence for undersea explorers in the outdated model of Jacques Costeau, expressed in THE LIFE AQUATIC and RUSHMORE, and Cameron’s much more masculine-coded urge to conquer the depths harnessing advanced technology for his pursuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Resurrection (1997) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_resurrection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien_resurrection/</guid>
      <description>At the end of the film, the Newborn is violently sucked through a tiny hole into Earth’s upper atmosphere. This film feels like trying to suck the Alien franchise through a much-diminished perspective to become a generic and misogynistic blockbuster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliver (1993) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sliver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sliver/</guid>
      <description>SLIVER wants to be about voyeurism, surveillance, and power. But gesturing towards themes while not saying anything substantive about them is not enough for thematic resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asteroid City (2023) - 105 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</guid>
      <description>ASTEROID CITY serves as something of an artistic statement for this period of Wes Anderson’s filmmaking, overtly discussing existential themes around meaning and, in particular, finding meaning through art that emphasise Anderson’s complicating of modernism and postmodernism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raiders!: The Story of the Greatest Fan Film Ever Made (2015) - 93 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/raiders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/raiders/</guid>
      <description>Like ALIEN ON STAGE and A BUNCH OF AMATEURS, RAIDERS! is a charming insight into amateur filmmaking that reveals the importance of creative outlets for ordinary people outside the big-budget industrial systems of mainstream filmmaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robinson in Space (1997) - 78 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/robinson_in_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/robinson_in_space/</guid>
      <description>“It’s always difficult coming back to England[&amp;hellip;]”.
Patrick Keiller’s peripatetic essay films remind me of the best of David Foster Wallace’s creative non-fiction (his visits to the State Fair, the pornography convention, and the cruise) in their style and digressive nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still: A Michael J. Fox Movie (2023) - 95 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/still/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/still/</guid>
      <description>A sensitive and joyously optimistic documentary about living with a condition in an industry that punishes things it sees as disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Moves (2013) - 112 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/night_moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/night_moves/</guid>
      <description>If you were scheduling an eco-”terrorism” double-bill of NIGHT MOVES with HOW TO BLOW UP A PIPELINE, you’d have to screen NIGHT MOVES first so that its languid pace wasn’t a comedown after the extreme tension of PIPELINE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archipelago (2010) - 114 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/archipelago/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/archipelago/</guid>
      <description>Joanna Hogg has a tremendous skill for representing the self-inflicted emotional agonies of the English upper-middle class that others may find self-indulgent but that I find quietly horrifying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London (1994) - 85 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/london/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/london/</guid>
      <description>“It seemed there was no longer anything a Conservative government could do to cause it to be voted out of office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien³ (1992) - 114 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/alien3/</guid>
      <description>David Fincher gets a lot better and a lot more subtle at hiding his disdain for his films’ ‘airport bestseller’ source material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Know Me? (2009) - 82 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/do_you_know_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/do_you_know_me/</guid>
      <description>In Paul T. Goldman, director Jason Woliner unravels the life and works of Paul Finkelman, a delusional but affable man whose experiences of life revolve outwards into bizarre and fantastical pastiches of crime dramas and blockbuster action films.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse (2023) - 140 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/across_the_spider-verse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/across_the_spider-verse/</guid>
      <description>Visually stunning and manages to step up the formal experimentation in cinematic animation that made INTO THE SPIDER-VERSE so outstanding. Miles (Shameik Moore) has a strong arc that does more than recapitulate the first film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medusa Deluxe (2022) - 101 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/medusa_deluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/medusa_deluxe/</guid>
      <description>The taut script and one-shot cinematography build tension terrifically in the first half. Like Philip Barantini’s BOILING POINT, it feels as if the rooms are filling up with too much gas and will inevitably burst into flames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touching the Void (2003) - 106 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/touching_the_void/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/touching_the_void/</guid>
      <description>I love mountains and have a real weakness for mountaineering documentaries. What distinguishes TOUCHING THE VOID from American-produced documentaries about Nepalese or American mountaineers is its attention to detail and its emotional rawness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confess, Fletch (2022) - 98 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/confess_fletch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/confess_fletch/</guid>
      <description>Just fine. A whodunnit murder mystery comedy that doesn’t stand up to recent takes on the genre like KNIVES OUT or SEE HOW THEY RUN but manages to skate along nicely on Jon Hamm’s charm and screen presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aliens (1986) - 137 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aliens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aliens/</guid>
      <description>After ALIEN, ALIENS put the franchise on a path that it didn’t have to take. There was a path available where ALIEN 2 continues with the New Hollywood feel of ALIEN, where it explores the mysterious cosmic Lovecraftian horror of LV-426 and the alien creature, where it leans into the elements that made ALIEN such a masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rye Lane (2023) - 82 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rye_lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rye_lane/</guid>
      <description>Beautifully shot, joyously inventive and subversive, emotionally real. Most importantly, RYE LANE captures the messy energy of South London, a place I called home for the better part of a decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainwashed: Sex-Camera-Power (2022) - 107 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/brainwashed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/brainwashed/</guid>
      <description>A film where the central thesis—that visual language in cinema, primarily shot composition, both perpetuates and is produced by patriarchal ways of seeing women that contribute to the mainstream cinema industry’s excess of economic discrimination against women and sexual assault against women—is obviously and inarguably true but the presentation of that thesis severely hampers the power of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 (2017) - 137 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/guardians_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/guardians_2/</guid>
      <description>Following on from GUARDIANS’s focus on the human, the overarching theme of the Guardians films is represented in the moment when Ego (Kurt Russell) tells Peter Quill (Chris Pratt) that while he’s alive Peter is a god and if Peter kills him he’ll be just like everybody else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy (2014) - 121 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/guardians_of_the_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/guardians_of_the_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>One shot that hit me this viewing was the quick shot towards the end of Dey (John C. Reilly) returning home after the obligatory Marvel third act battle to his family, his partner and his daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3 (2023) - 150 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/guardians_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/guardians_3/</guid>
      <description>My reaction to this film was heavily influenced by the fact I last saw the Guardians characters in the Avengers films where they were done dirty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rushmore (1998) - 93 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</guid>
      <description>Quite apart from the blossoming of his distinctive aesthetic (developed in collaboration with his long-time cinematographer Robert Yeoman who rarely gets enough credit for it), RUSHMORE provides early insights into many of the deeper themes and preoccupations that would go on to define Wes Anderson’s work: a focus on class and social status particularly with regards to the hierarchy of positions within esoteric institutions; an eye for the outsider figure and the social outcast; a fascination with under the sea and the life aquatic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Instinct (1992) - 127 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/basic_instinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/basic_instinct/</guid>
      <description>An interesting deconstruction of the masculinity inherent to film noir with a cop antagonist who is a bully, a prick, and a rapist presented alongside a be-gay-do-crimes queer femme fatale who is a confident badass and successful novelist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T2 Trainspotting (2017) - 117 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/t2_trainspotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/t2_trainspotting/</guid>
      <description>And then it’s twenty years later and you’re addicted to your nostalgia. You see ghosts of your own memories from the corner of your eyes on the streets you used to know and the songs you once knew so well are dim echoes that you can’t quite make out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trainspotting (1996) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/trainspotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/trainspotting/</guid>
      <description>“You&amp;rsquo;re not getting any younger, Mark. The world is changing. Music&amp;rsquo;s changing, even drugs are changing.”
A film that’s not about heroin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories We Tell (2012) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stories_we_tell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stories_we_tell/</guid>
      <description>More so than biological relationships or shared DNA, families are tapestries of histories and stories repeated again and again until they become legends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonor Will Never Die (Ang Pagbabalik ng Kwago) (2022) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/leonor_will_never_die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/leonor_will_never_die/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic mix of the dramas of the ‘10s combined with the exploitation films of the ‘70s. There is constant surprise in how layered and postmodern the film is willing to get but it always keeps a sense of playfulness and joy in its use of ‘70s exploitation tropes and metafictional devices right up until the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wet Hot American Summer (2001) - 97 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/wet_hot_american_summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/wet_hot_american_summer/</guid>
      <description>WET HOT AMERICAN SUMMER works best when it’s leaning into its silliness which unfortunately it doesn’t do frequently enough: the going-to-town montage is great; the subplot with Ken Marino’s character trying to get back to camp is gold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>They Came Together (2014) - 83 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/they_came_together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/they_came_together/</guid>
      <description>This film deserves the acclaim that ANCHORMAN has for some reason: undeniably up there with THE NAKED GUN and AIRPLANE! as a perfectly observed absurdist parody of its genre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bram Stoker’s Dracula (1992) - 128 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/dracula/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/dracula/</guid>
      <description>A horny fugue state of a film that adopts the novel’s epistolary format in a way that doesn’t really work on film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Little Stalker (2018) - 83 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/pretty_little_stalker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/pretty_little_stalker/</guid>
      <description>Loath though I am to suggest that this film should have more THE ROOM-level dialogue or more scenes of hunky shirtless men or more confusingly-staged melodrama or more scenes of the mother (Nicky Whelan) and son (Parker Mack) who look the same age but PRETTY LITTLE STALKERS really needed more establishing scenes for most of its central characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Trek: The Motion Picture (The Director’s Edition) (2022) - 137 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/star_trek_the_motion_picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/star_trek_the_motion_picture/</guid>
      <description>The only Star Trek film to grapple artistically with the unknowability and incomprehensibility of space with a particular focus on conveying the sheer scale of what could be out in the cosmos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronic (2019) - 101 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/synchronic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/synchronic/</guid>
      <description>This needed to be a few degrees closer to LIMITLESS on the magic-drug-subgenre spectrum. The core premise is interesting and I liked the film’s allusions to the racial implications of time travel but a film about time travel drugs really doesn’t need to be so dour and so bogged down in character work that really doesn’t add anything narratively or thematically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consecration (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/consecration/</guid>
      <description>A competently-produced Catholic horror film drawing on THE OMEN, THE WICKER MAN, and THE SHINING. There’s a kernel of an interesting idea at the core of the narrative but the script needed at least one more draft and perhaps would have benefitted from leaning into schlocky rather than self-serious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Causes Coughing (Fumer fait tousser) (2022) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/smoking_causes_coughing/</guid>
      <description>The superhero movie that Marvel won’t provide: well-lit, practical effects, strongly defined character relationships and romantic entanglements. Seemingly a commentary on a film market saturated with superhero movies: it feels like Quentin Dupieux had to make a superhero movie because nothing else gets made these days and it was the only way he could tell his absurdist stories about fish concerned with water pollution, a helmet that traps you in your thoughts, and a liquified human’s remains in a bucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The March on Rome (Marcia su Roma) (2022) - 97 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_march_on_rome/</guid>
      <description>Mark Cousins’ calm matter-of-fact narration doesn’t impose parallels between Italian fascist propaganda of the 1920s and today’s modern fascist propaganda but instead allows the obvious parallels to speak for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Father, The Devil (Mon Père, Le Diable) (2021) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/our_father_the_devil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/our_father_the_devil/</guid>
      <description>Ellie Foumbi’s debut feature makes terrific use of light and shadow for its story of trauma, revenge, and forgiveness. Marie (Babetida Sadjo) is haunted by her past trauma and sees it in the face of the new priest, Father Patrick (Souleymane Sy Savane).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Like Movies (2022) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/i_like_movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/i_like_movies/</guid>
      <description>Enjoyable as a sweet throw-back to quirky indie comedies of the ‘00s: a little NAPOLEON DYNAMITE and a dash of Kevin Smith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary (2022) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sanctuary/</guid>
      <description>SANCTUARY’s thoughtful depiction of fetish uses the sense of mystery behind sub-dom to bring the audience into the characters’ tangled power dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stone Turtle (2022) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stone_turtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/stone_turtle/</guid>
      <description>A mix of THE WICKER MAN and GROUNDHOG DAY that is an interesting blend of genres but adds up to less than the sum of its parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the Skin (2013) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/under_the_skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/under_the_skin/</guid>
      <description>An English woman struggles to find the M8 and gradually learns to see Scottish people as human beings.
The best representations of the alien and unknown use abstract visual poetry to represent the alien as not only unknown and unknowable but literally inconceivable to us within the bounds that we think in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Blow Up a Pipeline (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/how_to_blow_up_a_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>When I hear motorists and politicians complain about Extinction Rebellion or Just Stop Oil blocking roads, I think they ought to be thankful that the activists are engaging in such milquetoast actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ordinaries (2022) - 120 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_ordinaries/</guid>
      <description>THE ORDINARIES’ main character, Paula Feinmann (Fine Sendel), is a Supporting Character. Her father was a Main Character and she studies at the Main Character School to learn how to emote and how to draw the narrative’s attention to herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typist Artist Pirate King (2022) - 106 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/typist_artist_pirate_king/</guid>
      <description>An England seen through the prism of mental illness might be the truest view of England. TYPIST ARTIST PIRATE KING takes the audience on a psychogeographic journey along the length of England through the eyes of Audrey Amiss (Monica Dolan), a mentally ill British artist whose work was only recognised after her death in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Artist and the Wall of Death (2022) - 86 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_artist_and_the_wall_of_death/</guid>
      <description>A documentary about the theme of failure that abdicates its responsibility to discuss the actual human costs of failure. Stephen Skrynka is a visual artist obsessed with the Wall of Death, a fairground stunt attraction inside which a motorcyclist drives around the walls of a wooden cylinder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl (2023) - 87 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/girl/</guid>
      <description>Trapped in the intersection of mental health issues, trauma-induced anxiety, and contemporary Scottish racism, Grace (Déborah Lukumuena) seeks to insulate her and her daughter Ama (Le’Shantey Bonsu) against the world outside their high-rise flat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polite Society (2023) - 103 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/polite_society/</guid>
      <description>This year’s EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE: a joyous and hilarious blend of genres that uses irony and maximalist extravagance to speak sincerely about specific lived experience but in a universal way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightsiren (Svetlonoc) (2022) - 109 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/nightsiren/</guid>
      <description>Šarlota (Natália Germáni) returns to the mountain village where she grew up to find she’s an object of suspicion to the villagers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Astronaut (L’Astronaute) (2022) - 110 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_astronaut/</guid>
      <description>A charming celebration of the amateur. Jim Desforges (Nicolas Giraud) is an aeronautical engineer who dreams of launching the first amateur manned space flight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapy Dogs (2022) - 83 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/therapy_dogs/</guid>
      <description>High school is a shared nightmare. A unique subculture that most of us experienced but which we’ve forgotten the intensity of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcel the Shell with Shoes On (2021) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/marcel_the_shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/marcel_the_shell/</guid>
      <description>If you’d asked me ten years ago which viral short film do you least expect to get a feature-length adaptation, I would have said SALAD FINGERS (2004) followed by MARCEL THE SHELL WITH SHOES ON (2010).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other People’s Children (Les Enfants des autres) (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/other_peoples_children/</guid>
      <description>THE WORST PERSON IN THE WORLD is to thirty-somethings what OTHER PEOPLE’S CHILDREN is to forty-somethings: a mature emotionally resonant romantic comedy-drama that embraces the complexity of modern relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropic (Tropique) (2022) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tropic/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic event strikes the lake where two brothers are swimming, mutilating one and dooming his chances of taking part in Europe’s first space colonisation mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adopting Audrey (2021) - 92 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/adopting_audrey/</guid>
      <description>There’s a huge generational divide between baby boomers who are rich in capital but emotionally immature and millennials who are poor but emotionally fortified by multiple recessions and 21st century uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quatermass and the Pit (1967) - 97 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/quatermass_and_the_pit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/quatermass_and_the_pit/</guid>
      <description>An ancient horror buried deep beneath the clay of England waiting to unleash unimaginable evils from knowledges hidden for millennia in folk tales and superstitious legends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirrors (2008) - 111 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mirrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/mirrors/</guid>
      <description>When Kiefer Sutherland’s character says to Amy Smart’s character “Hey cis”, the film is unlocked as a trans allegory. Sutherland plays a trans man evidenced by his continual taking of pills and his recent alienation from former friends who seemingly can’t accept who he is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold Creek Manor (2003) - 118 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/cold_creek_manor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/cold_creek_manor/</guid>
      <description>A cautionary tale about moving to a community that you know nothing about, buying someone’s foreclosed home, stealing or selling all the stuff that they left, using their personal effects and family photos to start making a documentary film about them without their consent, and recording their vulnerable father in a convalescent home without his permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Witchfinder General (1968) - 87 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/witchfinder_general/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/witchfinder_general/</guid>
      <description>An England riven by political division turns to superstitious persecution of people for the sadistic thrill of victimising an out-group. A charismatic leader makes money off his sadistic prejudice while commanding those less educated than him to bully, torture, and kill women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye of the Devil (1966) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eye_of_the_devil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eye_of_the_devil/</guid>
      <description>Like the film’s wyrd combination of paganism and Christianity, it’s the combination of elements that elevates this early entry into what we’d now call the folk horror subgenre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Life (1979) - 99 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/real_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/real_life/</guid>
      <description>Albert Brooks’ early satire of reality television is almost too dry for its own good with a lot of the best parts carried entirely by Brooks’ delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Talking (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/women_talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/women_talking/</guid>
      <description>An adaptation less confident in its source material might have focused on what comes before and what happens after but WOMEN TALKING focuses in on the crux, the critical moments of decision that determine the fate of these women, their community, their families, and their religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gregory&#39;s Girl (1980) - 91 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/gregorys_girl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/gregorys_girl/</guid>
      <description>What’s it called? Cumbernauld! Bill Forsyth has an incredible ability to draw a whole character in only a few brush strokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copycat (1995) - 124 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/copycat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/copycat/</guid>
      <description>It’s a shame that this is so clearly made as a (apologies) copycat of THE SILENCE OF THE LAMBS since it actually has some interesting things to say about the influence of true crime on its audience and about serial killer fandom and it’s a shame a lot of that is watered down by the film’s adherence to the structure and tone of its predecessor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needle in a Timestack (2021) - 111 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/needle_in_a_timestack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/needle_in_a_timestack/</guid>
      <description>You wonder why they kept this title until you hear the screenplay’s idea of dialogue. For a film about time travel shenanigans, it’s ploddingly leaden and self-serious all the way through with dialogue either being outright expository or sour-faced portentousness (apart from the protagonist’s sister who actually speaks quite naturally usually about her quote best friend unquote).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Old School (2022) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/my_old_school/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/my_old_school/</guid>
      <description>When I was at school, a teacher wrote the word ‘prat’ on a pupil’s forehead in permanent marker. I wasn’t in the class where this happened but it became legend throughout the school, passed on through gossip in the corridors and the schoolyard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/who_framed_roger_rabbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/who_framed_roger_rabbit/</guid>
      <description>Still looks incredible: not just the mixing of animation and live-action elements but the period 1940s LA production design and the animation itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bunch of Amateurs (2022) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_bunch_of_amateurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/a_bunch_of_amateurs/</guid>
      <description>No horror film builds dread in quite the same way as idly noticing from a date in a brief shot that this film starts in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the Beauty and the Bloodshed (2022) - 121 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/all_the_beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/all_the_beauty/</guid>
      <description>An exploration not just of the Sackler family and their role in the opioid crisis and the art world but of how alternative communities live, thrive, and survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aftersun (2022) - 102 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aftersun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/aftersun/</guid>
      <description>“And there’s this feeling, once you leave where you grew up, that you don’t totally belong there again.” When I was a kid in the ‘90s, we&amp;rsquo;d go on family holidays to resorts in places like Majorca and Malta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primal Fear (1996) - 129 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/primal_fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/primal_fear/</guid>
      <description>PRIMAL FEAR contains some of the understated hallmarks of ‘90s thrillers: an obsession with property development; corruption that goes up to the highest levels of local government; questionable treatment of mental health issues; women that exist only in the orbit of men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Torture Chamber of Dr. Sadism (Die Schlangengrube und das Pendel) (1967) - 85 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/torture_chamber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/torture_chamber/</guid>
      <description>A West German B-movie horror, the best part of which is the interesting production design from the paintings influenced by Hieronymous Bosch to the locations evocative of Dark Souls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saint Omer (2022) - 123 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saint_omer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/saint_omer/</guid>
      <description>Quiet devastation erupts in discrete moments of an otherwise drawn-out trial. Alice Diop shows the processes of institutional justice in all their long, slow, and wordy reality with long shots on one person talking, defending herself, and repeating her life story for the court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade (1989) - 127 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/last_crusade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/last_crusade/</guid>
      <description>These days, a huge amount of money would be spent on special effects to make the boat chase actually look like it’s taking place in Venice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tár (2022) - 158 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tar/</guid>
      <description>Cate Blanchett plays Lydia Tár as a charming, authoritative, magnetic, and terrible person. We’re fully immersed in the life and perspective of a deeply unpleasant person and there’s a complex catharsis as the film charts her downfall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enys Men (2022) - 96 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/enys_men/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/enys_men/</guid>
      <description>A 1970s BBC British horror that has fallen through time to be released in 2023. The Volunteer (Mary Woodvine) undertakes the same ritual each and every day and it gradually becomes clear that she’s not a botanist but something deeper—something older—and that the flower she’s protecting is something more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eo (2022) - 86 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/eo/</guid>
      <description>EO directed by Jerzy Skolimowski uses the language of cinema to push us to empathise with a non-human protagonist and therefore expand our sense of subjectivity to cover the perspective of its titular donkey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rashomon (羅生門) (1950) - 88 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rashomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rashomon/</guid>
      <description>A post-apocalyptic period piece filmed in the context of the nuclear annihilation of two cities and 220,000 people, RASHOMON strips down humanity until it finds cynicism, deceit, selfishness, and despair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bonfire of the Vanities (1990) - 125 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bonfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bonfire/</guid>
      <description>If you set out to purposefully miscast a film, you couldn’t do a better job than THE BONFIRE OF THE VANITIES did inadvertently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klute (1971) - 114 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/klute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/klute/</guid>
      <description>A great performance from Jane Fonda as a sex worker whose reward for navigating a paranoid world of shadowy figures and sexual assault is to end up with John Klute (Donald Sutherland), the most boring man alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glengarry Glen Ross (1992) - 100 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/glengarry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/glengarry/</guid>
      <description>Like THE BANSHEES OF INISHERIN, GLENGARRY GLEN ROSS feels like a play in that it’s carried by its terrific dialogue and performances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
