<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GFF2024 on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2024/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GFF2024 on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/gff2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hoard (2023) - 126 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/hoard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/hoard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a film about hoarding and collecting excess, it’s almost appropriate how much cruft there is in HOARD that could have been edited out and pared down. This could have been a much tighter film about the looming spectre of family mental illness and how love and sexual awakening brings these chaotic demons to the surface. The central idea of the “catalogue of love” is heartbreaking in its tenderness and its grotesque implications and the film needed to be streamlined for that emotional throughline. Both Saura Lightfoot Leon and Lily-Beau Leach are terrific as Maria, bringing the strange poetry of her illness to life in a way that’s as beautiful as it is disturbing. HOARD just needed less of the excess around that central emotional structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woken (2024) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/woken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/woken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A pandemic sci-fi thriller that might be too much for those exhausted by the last few years but that offers an eerie atmosphere and some interesting twists and turns. Sometimes it’s hard to tell if I get frustrated by clumsy tropes because I’ve watched too many films or if it’s an unfortunate element of the script. Either way it’s a shame that this starts so promisingly and descends into a third act of genre tropes, most egregiously the computer that auto-plays the most narratively pertinent recordings when it turns on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La chimera (2023) - 133 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/la_chimera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/la_chimera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LA CHIMERA has an odd tempo, like a half-remembered story from long ago that becomes clearer when there’s a little rhyme to help you along. Arthur (Josh O’Connor) is a rogue archaeologist, robbing graves and raiding Etruscan tombs. His quasi-mystic gift for finding lost things through a weird dowsing ritual gives the film a mythic quality, rich with allegory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorcery (Brujería) (2023) - 101 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sorcery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/sorcery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SORCERY (BRUJERÍA) tells the fascinating story of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4000/anthrovision.3946&#34;&gt;La Recta Provincia witch trial in 19th century Chile&lt;/a&gt; in a dull and dreary way. There’s resonant anti-colonial themes and an amazing performance from newcomer Valentina Véliz Caileo but the whole film around it feels so lifeless and flat, a slow burn that doesn’t lead to any explosion. SORCERY is interesting as an attempt to do what critics said &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/killers_of_the_flower_moon/&#34;&gt;KILLERS OF THE FLOWER MOON&lt;/a&gt; should do and show the murder of Indigenous people by white settlers from the perspective of the victims rather than the murderers but the overall result is disappointingly forgettable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lousy Carter (2023) - 80 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lousy_carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/lousy_carter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lousy Carter (David Krumholtz) is dying and Bob Byington’s film invites us to ask, who cares? On paper, he’s an unlikeable American literature professor, a narcissist with few friends who halfheartedly pursues a relationship with a student. But David Krumholtz brings him to life with a genuine humanism and dry charm. It’s a comedy that is wonderfully ambivalent about its own existence with the ultimate joke being that, despite openly hating itself, an audience can watch it and enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love Lies Bleeding (2024) - 104 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/love_lies_bleeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/love_lies_bleeding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last two seconds of SAINT MAUD prove Rose Glass is a visceral filmmaker and that’s on full aural and visual display in LOVE LIES BLEEDING: we hear the sounds of muscles stretching and throats constricting; we see jawbones breaking and blood spatter squelching. This visceral cinematic expression is in service of a modern-day THELMA AND LOUISE where queerness isn’t the backbone of the narrative but just one element of this love and revenge story. In different ways, Lou (Kristen Stewart) and Jackie (Katy O’Brian) both learn to embrace the metaphorical monsters that society has turned them into and use that self-knowledge for liberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restore Point (Bod obnovy) (2023) - 111 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/restore_point/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/restore_point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_creator/&#34;&gt;THE CREATOR&lt;/a&gt;, RESTORE POINT (BOD OBNOVY) showcases what CGI visual effects can be produced on a small budget in a way that puts much more expensive Hollywood blockbusters to shame. The BLADE RUNNER 2049-type skyline and the MINORITY REPORT slick technology all look great and fit into the world without obvious CGI aesthetics or horrendously offputting green-screen. Unfortunately the story also liberally borrows plot beats from other sci-fi films ultimately making the whole thing feel very familiar and very predictable. If you’ve seen I, ROBOT or Bodies, then you’ve seen this and it won’t surprise you to learn that the corporation behind the future technology might not be entirely trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vourdalak (Le Vourdalak) (2023) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_vourdalak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_vourdalak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Though a little off-putting, there’s something charming about the vourdalak puppet who looks something like a Jan Švankmajer creation crossed with one of Mike Mignola’s skeletons from &lt;em&gt;Hellboy in Hell&lt;/em&gt;. This strange puppet takes you out of the film but in a way that is at least interesting to look at and charmingly analogue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tummy Monster (2023) - 85 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tummy_monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/tummy_monster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rub your tummy or I’ll think you’re an asshole. UNCUT GEMS in Glasgow: a tense, strange, and frequently hilarious psychological drama that gradually turns a ridiculous situation into the cosmic metaphysical horror of painful and anxious rebirth. Lorn Macdonald and Orlando Norman deliver terrific performances respectively as a hot mess of a tattoo artist and an anonymous popstar turned trickster god. It’s a wholly unexpected delight and a spectacularly confident debut feature from director Ciaran Lyons. Rub your tummy or I’ll think you’re an asshole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Burning Season (2023) - 89 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_burning_season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_burning_season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A love story told backwards taking us from the devastating impact of a couple’s long-running emotional affair to the tragedy that cemented their lives together in the first place. THE BURNING SEASON joins a long lineage of media that &lt;a href=&#34;https://hcommons.org/deposits/item/hc:56781&#34;&gt;I’ve discussed extensively elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; where trauma is represented through the depiction of non-linear time, through time warping around a traumatic event and pulling the characters back towards it like a black hole. A slight romantic drama made effective by some convincingly couple-y dialogue and performances that ground the central relationship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
