<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Harvest (2024) - 133 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/harvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/harvest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HARVEST is a period drama with the trappings of a folk horror and does not succeed as either. There’s no horror and the drama does not represent any particular period. It obliquely refers to the Highland Clearances without actually being embedded in the Scottish context of those events. HARVEST is an hour too long at the front and is poorly paced throughout, the characters are tediously obtuse, and the script loves to tell rather than show.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Luckiest Man in America (2024) - 90 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/luckiest_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/drafts/luckiest_man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An entertainingly tense dramatisation of a small-scale situation on a 1980s US game show. THE LUCKIEST MAN IN AMERICA has some fun nostalgia aesthetics emulating the look of old VHS recordings (it specifically brought to mind Patrick Cotnoir’s visual work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t0Bslw2hLzI&#34;&gt;this live reading of THE STAR WARS HOLIDAY SPECIAL&lt;/a&gt;). Paul Walter Hauser carries the film with a wonderfully ambiguous charm where you never quite know if he’s a charming happy-go-lucky guy or a snake oil salesman. Patti Harrison is sadly wasted but it’s always a joy to see her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
