<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wes-Anderson on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/wes-anderson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wes-Anderson on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/wes-anderson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Poison (2023) - 17 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/poison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/poison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deliciously tense and delightfully staged, the uncharacteristically wobbly camerawork and rapid-pace dialogue all build tension so well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rat Catcher (2023) - 17 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_rat_catcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_rat_catcher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On paper, the most disturbing of these Anderson adaptaions of Dahl but this one didn’t quite click.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Swan (2023) - 17 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_swan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_swan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A wonderful microcosm of Anderson unearthing sincerity from layers of artifice while drawing attention to the artifice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wonderful Story of Henry Sugar (2023) - 42 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/henry_sugar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/henry_sugar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A compelling experiment in marrying Anderson and Yeoman’s aesthetic to a straight adaptation although Dahl’s original text contains several Anderson hallmarks: nested structure; quick-wittedness. Very significant right now to hear Sugar saying “I don’t want to be the richest man on Earth.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hotel Chevalier (2007) - 13 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/hotel_chevalier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/hotel_chevalier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Enigmatically enticing as a little crystallisation of mid-Anderson aesthetic. Would work better standalone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Darjeeling Limited (2007) - 92 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_darjeeling_limited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_darjeeling_limited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to read THE DARJEELING LIMITED as self-indulgent: three wealthy white American men searching for a spiritual experience in a culture with which they make no effort to engage. But I think that self-indulgence is both personal and self-reflective for the three white men who wrote it. The film is self-aware enough to laugh at its protagonists while remaining grounded in their humanity and the humanity of those around them. In that way, it’s a very generous film about trauma, familial hurt, and emotional repression, lesser than &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_royal_tenenbaums/&#34;&gt;TENENBAUMS&lt;/a&gt; but meaningful nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Royal Tenenbaums (2001) - 110 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_royal_tenenbaums/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_royal_tenenbaums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went into this rewatch thinking that this might drop in &lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/simonxix/list/wes-anderson-ranking/&#34;&gt;my Wes Anderson ranking&lt;/a&gt;. If anything, I’m considering moving it higher. Multiple scenes in TENENBAUMS are among the most transcendently beautiful filmmaking of Anderson’s entire career: notably young Richie Tenenbaum (Arianna Turturro) releasing Mordecai; the ‘These Days’ shot; Chas (Ben Stiller) releasing his pain to his father. TENENBAUMS is a profoundly moving depiction of emotional repression and stunted family dynamics that doesn’t hold your hand in explaining the emotional complexities of its characters’ inner lives. It’s also the best cinematic adaptation of David Foster Wallace’s &lt;em&gt;Infinite Jest&lt;/em&gt; that could ever exist (more so for only ever being coincidentally(?) similar).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fantastic Mr. Fox (2009) - 87 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/fantastic_mr_fox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/fantastic_mr_fox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Until the film’s final scene, I would have said that this is, surprisingly, Wes Anderson’s most anti-capitalist film: the contrast between the coldly metallic heavy industrialisation of Boggis, Bunce, and Bean’s farms and the warm autumnal palette of the animals’ home; Mr. Fox’s (George Clooney) embrace of his wild animal nature. The last shot, a long shot of a huge big-box supermarket, complicates this reading. Has Mr. Fox in some sense been domesticated by neoliberal convenience? Is capitalist normativity just a different kind of fox-trap for him?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The French Dispatch (2021) - 108 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_french_dispatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_french_dispatch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remembered this as the slightest of Wes Anderson’s live-action scripts with Roman Coppola, most notable for the extreme precision of the film’s Andersonian clockwork diorama world and evocativeness of music and visuals. Yet I was moved to tears by the scene between Roebuck Wright (Jeffrey Wright) and Lt. Nescaffier (Stephen Park) which exemplifies all the film’s themes—which I’d either forgotten or missed the first time—around loneliness and yearning for human connection. That brief moment of connection between a foreign immigrant and an expatriate homosexual both “[s]eeking something missing, missing something left behind” and hoping to “find what eluded us in the places we once called home”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bottle Rocket (1996) - 91 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bottle_rocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bottle_rocket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like the main characters, this film has a charm and a sincerity that are both beguiling even while it settles into a diffuseness that feels a little frustrating. There’s a good mix of Coen Brothers’ postmodern sensibility with Godard’s rebellious young man archetype but this also takes on some of the worst qualities of both in its sense of youthful aimlessness. It didn’t really work for me but it’s interesting to see the embryonic elements of Wes Anderson’s aesthetic steadily emerge particularly in the sequences reshot from the short film version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bottle Rocket (1994) - 14 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bottle_rocket_1994/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/bottle_rocket_1994/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short’s conciseness and energy work better to convey the themes than the feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moonrise Kingdom (2012) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/moonrise_kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/moonrise_kingdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an essay for the Criterion Collection Blu-ray, Isabel Folger writes that “Moonrise Kingdom shows that with the right people in your life, you won’t feel misunderstood.” There are some emotional moments that are so powerful that they justify entire films about them. MOONRISE KINGDOM is about that moment that you are seen—truly seen—for the first time. When Sam (Jared Gilman) sees Suzy (Kara Hayward), it doesn’t matter that they’ve never fit in before, that they’ve been labelled “emotionally disturbed” or “very troubled”. They find that one other person and suddenly fit just right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Life Aquatic with Steve Zissou (2004) - 119 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_life_aquatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_life_aquatic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2023_Titan_submersible_incident&#34;&gt;The Titan submersible incident&lt;/a&gt; prompted a response by James Cameron highlighting his approach to underwater exploration. I’m struck by the contrast between Wes Anderson’s almost childlike reverence for undersea explorers in the outdated model of Jacques Costeau, expressed in THE LIFE AQUATIC and &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/&#34;&gt;RUSHMORE&lt;/a&gt;, and Cameron’s much more masculine-coded urge to conquer the depths harnessing advanced technology for his pursuit. Anderson’s view of someone who would explore the ocean is far more melancholic with Zissou cast as a tragic figure: not a hero, but someone ineluctably human and flawed, deeply so. Ultimately both Zissou and Cameron must face the same question when confronted with the immense indifference of the oceanic world beyond them, “I wonder if it remembers me?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asteroid City (2023) - 105 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ASTEROID CITY serves as something of an artistic statement for this period of Wes Anderson’s filmmaking, overtly discussing existential themes around meaning and, in particular, finding meaning through art that emphasise Anderson’s complicating of modernism and postmodernism. When Adrien Brody’s director character says that the meaning doesn’t matter, he’s talking through the fourth wall to viewers alienated by Anderson’s idiosyncratic aesthetics. ASTEROID CITY tells the viewer not only how to read it but how to read all of Anderson’s work by openly stating that how the viewer approaches his films is critical to how the works produce sincerity with and through their ironic postmodern conceits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rushmore (1998) - 93 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite apart from the blossoming of his distinctive aesthetic (developed in collaboration with his long-time cinematographer Robert Yeoman who rarely gets enough credit for it), RUSHMORE provides early insights into many of the deeper themes and preoccupations that would go on to define Wes Anderson’s work: a focus on class and social status particularly with regards to the hierarchy of positions within esoteric institutions; an eye for the outsider figure and the social outcast; a fascination with under the sea and the life aquatic. A story of a weird little guy told weirdly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
