<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wes-Anderson on Reviews Per Minute</title>
    <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/wes-anderson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wes-Anderson on Reviews Per Minute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/categories/wes-anderson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moonrise Kingdom (2012) - 94 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/moonrise_kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/moonrise_kingdom/</guid>
      <description>In an essay for the Criterion Collection Blu-ray, Isabel Folger writes that “Moonrise Kingdom shows that with the right people in your life, you won’t feel misunderstood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life Aquatic with Steve Zissou (2004) - 119 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_life_aquatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/the_life_aquatic/</guid>
      <description>The Titan submersible incident prompted a response by James Cameron highlighting his approach to underwater exploration. I’m struck by the contrast between Wes Anderson’s almost childlike reverence for undersea explorers in the outdated model of Jacques Costeau, expressed in THE LIFE AQUATIC and RUSHMORE, and Cameron’s much more masculine-coded urge to conquer the depths harnessing advanced technology for his pursuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asteroid City (2023) - 105 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/asteroid_city/</guid>
      <description>ASTEROID CITY serves as something of an artistic statement for this period of Wes Anderson’s filmmaking, overtly discussing existential themes around meaning and, in particular, finding meaning through art that emphasise Anderson’s complicating of modernism and postmodernism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rushmore (1998) - 93 mins</title>
      <link>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reviewsperminute.simonxix.com/posts/rushmore/</guid>
      <description>Quite apart from the blossoming of his distinctive aesthetic (developed in collaboration with his long-time cinematographer Robert Yeoman who rarely gets enough credit for it), RUSHMORE provides early insights into many of the deeper themes and preoccupations that would go on to define Wes Anderson’s work: a focus on class and social status particularly with regards to the hierarchy of positions within esoteric institutions; an eye for the outsider figure and the social outcast; a fascination with under the sea and the life aquatic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
